# Ahmed Talaat

Software Developer / Project Manager | +2 01020181885 ahmed.talaat.92@hotmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedtalaat92/

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Riskline

Technical Project Manager/Assisting Team Lead August 2020 to Present

Acting as a Project Manager managing my team tasks and holding daily standup meetings and scrums for my team and maintaining development lifecycle and timeline also assisting team lead in reviewing code and helping other developers when needed. our own company Product and Services:

- https://riskline.com/

#### Creiden co.

Senior Backend Developer

September 2019 to August 2020

Developed applications using Backend languages and frameworks mainly (PHP) with Laravel, Symfony and Wordpress frameworks. some of the projects I worked on:

- https://eaconomy.com/
- https://stacksmarket.co

### Objects co.

Backend Developer

June 2018 - September 2019

Worked on various backend projects using backend languages including PHP and Node.js assisting my team in developing mobile and web applications examples:

- Belshifa mobile app
- 24/7 Application a transportation and delivery app for Saudi arabian market -Evoline (https://www.evoline.com/) A euro based website specialized in selling workstations.
- Landfleet a website for a petroleum company managing their fleets moving around according to clients requests.

### Other Projects:

- Groupo5 ( A storage handling website based in Spain. )
- MRM (An advertising agency website.)
- Care-Project ( Canadian company internal web application handling employees benefits system and vacations )

## EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

### **Arab Academy for Science and Technology**

Alexandria Egypt Bachelors degree in B.A (E-commerce) 2016

Grade: Very Good

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A hardworking and collaborative Web developer / Project manager with over 5 years of experience. Passionate about coding, engaging in software development & interested in technology and the ability to create.. A Hard worker and a team player who is all for working in teams and collaborating.

## SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

PHP (symfony - laravel - wordpress) -Node.js - Express - Restful API's -Mongodb - MySQL - JIRA - Clickup- -RedMine - Git - Javascript - Typescript -Google workspace - HTML - CSS -JQuery - Linux - Lampp - Elastic Search -Google API's - Firebase - PHP Storm -Webstorm

## CONTACT INFO

ahmed.talaat.92@hotmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedtalaat92 www,github.com/hadress92 Alexandria, Egypt (+2) 010 20181885